<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Echosounder on Wu-Jung Lee @APL-UW</title>
    <link>https://leewujung.github.io/tags/echosounder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Echosounder on Wu-Jung Lee @APL-UW</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Wu-Jung Lee</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://leewujung.github.io/tags/echosounder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching a solar eclipse using OOI sonar</title>
      <link>https://leewujung.github.io/2018/07/30/watching-a-solar-eclipse-using-ooi-sonar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leewujung.github.io/2018/07/30/watching-a-solar-eclipse-using-ooi-sonar/</guid>
      <description>This is something I wrote in 2017 right after coming back from my first trip with the OOI cabled array team. Didn&amp;rsquo;t have the website up then and things got busy, so I forgot about it&amp;hellip; 😱
On VISIONS&amp;rsquo;18, now seems about the time to dust this off. The echogram from the echosounder still looks awesome after a year, so read on! 😎
Watching a solar eclipse is a powerful experience for most people, and that is no exception for those of us who sailed on R/V Roger Revelle during the VISIONS’17 expedition - the annual service cruise to maintain the hundreds of instruments installed on the Cabled Array of the Ocean Observatories Initiative (OOI) network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scooping up zooplankton from the ocean</title>
      <link>https://leewujung.github.io/2018/07/26/scooping-up-zooplankton-from-the-ocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leewujung.github.io/2018/07/26/scooping-up-zooplankton-from-the-ocean/</guid>
      <description>This is my second time sailing with the OOI Cabled Array team from UW APL and the School of Oceanography, with a mission to scoop up some zooplankton from the ocean. These zooplankton samples will serve as verification data &amp;ndash; or “ground truth” &amp;ndash; for the cabled Bio-acoustic Sonars (ZPLSC-B) on the OOI Endurance Array. On Leg 4 of VISIONS&amp;rsquo;18, we only had time to visit the Oregon offshore cabled site, so that&amp;rsquo;s where we towed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>